johnlewis.co.uk 2018-01-26

# Security & privacy

## Your password

We do appreciate that remembering passwords can be tricky, but setting effective and secure passwords on all the sites you use is vital in combating possible fraudulent activity using your personal details.

It's best to avoid using the same password for each of your online accounts, because if a criminal gains access to it, all your accounts could be at risk. Multiple passwords keep you safer.

When you set a password, it's a good idea to use a mix of numbers and characters, and something that's very personal to you. Most sites these days will set a minimum number of characters to use, but do avoid using obvious phrases like “password”, or your name, or phone number. In this example, we've used a well-known Shakespearian quotation to illustrate the kind of phrase you might want to choose (read it aloud and it will make sense!)

It's a good idea to change your passwords on a regular basis, especially for sites you use frequently and which involve financial transactions.

If you ever get a request to reveal your password for an online site, don't respond as legitimate sites and services won't ask you to send them passwords via email. You may be tempted to share passwords with close family, but do keep in mind there's always a risk they could pass information on inadvertently or share it with someone else.

You can re-set your password on johnlewis.com at any time by signing into your account and choosing the Edit your password option. If you've forgotten your password, just enter your email address on the 'Forgotten your password' page, and we'll email you your password information. Then simply follow the instructions in the email to change your password.

It's a good idea at this point to change your password to something that's as secure as possible. If you decide to change your johnlewis.com account password, or if we prompt you to do so, we'll ask you to set one with no fewer than 8 characters, to include a minimum of one upper and one lower case letter, and at least one number.

For more information on online safety and passwords, there are a number of useful websites such as [Get Safe Online](http://www.getsafeonline.org/), [Microsoft Safety & Security](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/security-essentials-download), [Google good to know](http://www.google.co.uk/safetycenter/)

Back to top

## Computer security

Keep yourself safe from malware and viruses with adequate, up to date security on your computer. You can usually download free basic protection from providers such as AVG and McAfee, but for more comprehensive cover, it's best to choose security software, which of course you can buy from us. Keep your software switched on and up to date, and make sure that your Windows operating system has the latest Microsoft updates. It's a good idea to run regular scans on your computer.

When you're opening emails, be careful. Don't click on links to download files or open attachments you haven't asked for, or aren't expecting, as they may contain viruses.

Back up all your files so they're available if the worst happens and your computer is infected by a virus. Read this feature for some tips on how to do this.

Back to top

## Privacy promise

Your privacy is of the highest importance to us, and we promise never to release your personal details to any outside company for their mailing or marketing purposes.

When you make a purchase from our website, we do collect certain personal information from you (for example: your name, email address, payment address and details). All such information is held on secure servers. John Lewis complies fully with all applicable Data Protection and consumer legislation, and we'll treat all your personal information as fully confidential. Find out more.

In order to serve you most efficiently, reputable third-party banking (including PayPal) and distribution institutions handle our credit card transactions and order fulfilment. They receive the information needed to verify and authorise your payment card and to process your order. All such organisations are under strict obligation to keep your personal information private.

To read more on how your personal data is going to be handled, read our full Privacy Policy incorporated in our Terms and Conditions.

We also use banner advertising on other websites to present you with products we think may be of interest to you, based on your browsing history. Find out more here.

## Customer contact promise

The John Lewis Partnership includes John Lewis, Waitrose and John Lewis Financial Services. We'd love you to be among the first to receive exciting offers and news about our products and services. We do this in various ways including email, post, SMS and phone, but only if you would like us to. Don't forget to visit us online, in-store and via social media for other special offers.

Your privacy is very important to us which is why we make sure you're always in control of what we do with your personal information.

This is our simple customer contact promise:

  * We'll never pass your personal details to anyone outside the John Lewis Partnership for them to use for their own marketing purposes
  * We'll only ever use your details to help you make the most of what we have to offer. That means things like:
    * Tips and guidance to help you get the best out of your products
    * News to help you make informed choices in the things you buy
    * Details of new products and services
    * Special offers
    * Or simply, to get your feedback
  * We will make sure our contact with you is relevant based on the information you give us. 
  * You can opt out at any time. All you need to do is change your Promotional Preferences in My Account. But remember, if you do ‘opt out' of receiving this information you could miss out on offers and news.
  * We'll always comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 and all other relevant legislation. You can see how we're doing this by reading our full Privacy Policy.

Please do let us know if your details change so that we can continue to stay in touch.

Back to top

## Your transaction security

### johnlewis.com is secure

We realise how important it is to securely store any information that you provide. johnlewis.com maintains the highest levels of security. Our site uses high-level SSL encryption technology, the most advanced security software currently available for online transactions. You can therefore rest assured that we take the privacy and security of your payment and personal details very seriously.

You can tell whether a page is secure as 'https' will replace the 'http' at the front of the www.johnlewis.com in your browser address window. A small locked padlock will also appear in the bottom bar of your browser window.

To give you even more confidence in shopping online with johnlewis.com, our checkout process uses Verified by Visa, Mastercard® SecureCode™. and American Express SafeKey SM. These services enhance your existing card account against unauthorised use when you shop with us.

To use these services, you must first register with the bank or other organisation that issued your card. Click on the images below to find out more:

Once you've registered and created your own private password with your card issuer, you'll be prompted automatically at checkout to provide this password each time you make a purchase.

**Please note:** Your Verified by Visa, Mastercard® SecureCode™ or American Express SafeKey SM password is different from your johnlewis.com account password. We don't have access to card issuer passwords.

### Using WiFi in public places 

Using an unsecured network in a public place can be risky as unauthorised people may try to intercept anything you're doing online. We recommend you only connect to secure wireless networks that you trust, and to always be aware of the risks associated with using public WiFi. 

Back to top

## Phishing

Phishing is the practice of tricking someone into giving confidential information. Examples include falsely claiming to be a legitimate company when sending an e-mail to a user, in an attempt to get the user to send private information that will be used for identity theft and fraud.

We'll never ask you to send any personal details via email. If we require such details, for security reasons we'll ask you to contact us by phone. Should you receive an email claiming to be from johnlewis.com requesting this kind of information, please don't respond, but do let us know about it.

Back to top
